[Music] making actual gelato with
just these two ingredients in your
Ninja creamy is possible.... let's
have a look at how we do [Music] it.
Gelato isn't anything fancy, it comes from Italy
it's a different type of ice cream all right so
American ice cream has higher overrun slightly
lower sugar much higher fat gelato has much lower
fat much higher sugar much less overrun that's
what July 2 is that that is the main differences
between ice cream and gelato that's it you can
play around with that you can increase overrun
a gelato and it will still be just as nice but the
sugar content being really high is something that
people are quite happy to forget about gelat in
the world where everyone is obsessed with being
healthy they want to eat gelato because they
think it's something special and in reality
what's better for you sugar or fat well neither
really they're both as bad as bad for you as the
next but we make that judgment when we make our
ice cream because it's enjoyable and something in
life has to be enjoyable if you subscribe to this
channel you know that that that's all I do I just
do ice creams gelato and sawway and that kind
of stuff that that's all this channel is about
um I am going to start doing some other recipes
and i' got a really really nice one coming up in
a few weeks which is reminiscent of my days
back in the UK but we can go to the store
and buy half and half and a can of condensed
milk or sweetened condensed milk same thing
and turn that into amazing gelato let me show
you how Bloody easy this really is right quick
sip we need 550 G of this which is this in cups
all right we don't even need to heat this up
that's a massive botle but that will do we we
don't need to heat this up we're not adding
stabilizers this time because this is about
doing this quickly say this has this is just
milk and cream nice Dairyland thank you for not
adding the other stuff so 550 g of half and half
this is 10% fat that's important 550 550 g 10%
fat is important because that is how we as ice
cream makers determine fat content sugar content
solids content milk solids nonfat all of that
stuff comes from knowing what you're putting into
your ice cream all right so all these uh social
media recipes for Ninja creamy that they just put
random stuff in and have no idea why then that's
why you're struggling to take your ninja creamy
ice cream churn it you know spin it put it back in
the freezer and it's like a block of ice cuz they
got no idea what they're talking about they got no
idea the intri of making ice cream it's actually
quite easy Once you break it down you just need to
understand a couple of little things so 550 g of
half and half and to that we're going to add 350
G which is this in cups of condensed milk and I'm
going to get a spoon and if my calculations are
correct that is an entire can so this is a 300 mil
can I love condensed milk of condensed
milk with this we need to add some kind
of flavor this is where the the thing comes
this is where the importance of knowing what
makes a good ice cream good we're going to
use extract but we need to use an alcohol
based extract because that alcohol is what is
going to make this soft enough to put back in
your freezer and have another day without
this it will go too hard all right so you
can use whatever extract you fancy it just needs
to be alcohol based I've got lemon here hazelnut
here I'm actually going to divide it and do
one of each now there is let me put this in the
[Music] fridge there is something
you can do to make this even
better invert sugar this is like a dirty
invert sugar in respect that is I have no
idea how it's made um it's got vanillin in it
and salt it still does the job and it's cheap
and you can get it from basically anywhere
this and it's covered in sticky stuff this
is specialized so this is 4de glucose syrup if
you really want to up your ice cream game get
some of this all right an invert sugar does
something very special to ice creams gelato
it it gives it texture that you can't achieve
without using it it it gives something that
is super smooth uh slightly more luxurious than
just using standard sugars um condensed milk is
one of these weird ingredients it's got so much
sugar in it that it that's why we don't need to
add anymore the heating process is actually done
at lower temperature but within a vacuum so you
don't get the invert sugar when using that so
if you don't want to use the invert sugar then
simply don't but I'm going to whoop we need 30
G for this mix right stir it so this mix with
the corn syrup or the glucose syrup or the invert
sugar whatever you're going to use this mix will
give us these stats Aus 12 serving temperature
99.1% fat 18.5% sugar 88.1% milk solid nonfat
35 .9% total solids 63.8% water with a PO 196 if
you don't use the corn syrup or invert sugar the
stats that you will have are A- 10 Centigrade
serving temperature 99.4% fat 16.7% sugar 88.3%
milk solids nonfat 43.6% solids and 65% water
with a pod of 170 if you don't know what any
of those numbers mean then don't worry about it
just make this if you are into your ice cream
and these stats are important that's what you're
going to get all right so this puts this firmly
in gelat territory now we're going to flavor both
of these we're going to take our tubs and put it
in there we go now what we can do is
just take a touch of our extract half
a teaspoon that that's all we need we
don't need any more half teaspoon like
2 G something like um I love Hazen ice cream
don't need any more than 2 G half teaspoon we
just don't there not enough in here to to
Warrant anymore my will that fit in there
no tiny
whisk all we're doing is [Music]
we're just Distributing that extract into the base
definitely lemon definitely hazelnut
we're good so let's pop these in the
freezer and we'll come back in however long
that takes probably what 4 [Applause] hours
right next day we've done the two flavors using
the extract lemon hazelnut we're going to do
the lemon one today and I'm going to use
some white chocolate as an addin so valona
Ivory let's get some of this [Applause] out
we've only got a single pint so I kind of I
don't want to get too mad but let's put that
there but you want to cut this up nice and
[Music] small there we go let me get my
phone so you can see how small that is
so there we go nice and small let's just
take a piece so you can see the size we
got if it's too big then it's like a massive
hard chunk of chocolate in your ice cream and
I mean I like that but hey not everyone does so
now that we've got that we can get our tub out the
freezer they both look the same
which one is it that one right
straight out the freezer let's get it
[Music] in little McFly there we go
in and let's get it [Music]
going man that thing's loud let's get our
spoon
low and we're going to take
our lemon half and half ice cream I mean
it smells delicious I love lemon ice cream
and you can you can use lemon zest
to do this if you don't want the
extract but the extract like I
said before you need that come
on you need that alcohol to balance
this freezing point out without the
alcohol without the alcohol the moment you
put it in the freezer after eating some
it's going to go rock solid and that's
something people other 99% of people
that do ninja creamy recipes don't tell
you is how to balance that freezing point
so that it doesn't go rock solid that's
why you're here ice cream Channel yay so
we've got our white chocolate in there
now we are just going to do our mix in
[Music]
God all just to stir in some
chocolate anyway turn that
off
let's get some dished out
let's get our spoon and I can now put this in
the freezer and it still be good in a week's
time said with a high level of sarcasm super nice
I mean it's low overrun so it's dense kind of ice
cream but hey it's super lemony really really
nice strong lemon smoke and see those pieces of
grown of white chocolate scattered throughout
and I am looking forward to trying this one
because you know I haven't had ice cream in
at least 5 minutes half and half condensed
milk then your extract alcohol-based extract if
you use the corn syrup and or glucose or invert
sugar it creates a much nicer kind of texture
if you don't they're both still gelato they're
both really good the the amount of sugar in
there is exactly as is required for gelato the
amount of fat content is exactly as required for
gelato gelato is lower overrun and actually this
benefits a ninja creamy because it produces
no overrun so you you kind of get something
a little bit more the lid's leaking you get
something a little bit more in line with what
ju like to should be it's still way too dense
but it's close enough let's try it super smooth
texture kind of fudgy this is
delicious white chocolate pieces big
enough so that you can actually bite
into them not so big they go rock solid super
refreshing it's 9:05 in the morning I'm going to
have lemon gelato with valona white chocolate for
breakfast do try this in your creamy you won't
be disappointed you can eat some put it in the
freezer it's going to be the same texture in days
it's not going to go rock solid you won't have
to respin it you'll be good to go whenever
you want it thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe and if you're
wondering what I'm going to do with the hazelnut
one I should use that in another video so make
sure you like And subscribe see you next time
a
[Music]